# Samuel Nigh

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-nigh

241 Fisk Street Pittsburgh, PA 15201 Phone: 724-816-8059 E-Mail: nighsam@gmail.com

Website: http://sam-nigh.tech

I am a graduate of Computer Science with deep Pittsburgh roots that has broad project and work experience in embedded software development, test automation, and web applications. I am interested in joining an organization in relevant areas that provide opportunities to deepen my knowledge and improve my skills.

## **Education**

## University of Pittsburgh Main Campus, Pittsburgh PA August 2014 to Present

- Major Computer Science, minor Italian Studies (completed).
- 3.62 GPA, Dean's List Freshman year, Sophomore year, Junior Spring 2016.
- Activities: Computer Science Club (Events Coordinator officer), National Society of Leadership and Success
- Six-week study abroad program for Italian Studies in Rome, Summer 2015.

## **Anticipated graduation date: April 2018**

## **Employment Experience**

### Embedded Systems Intern, Timesys Inc. May, 2017 to August, 2017

- Assigned to embedded engineering team responsible for incorporating customer and vendor requested enhancements.
- Verified and debugged automated driver testing for Timesys Factory board support packages.
- Updated and maintained resources and documentation for LinuxLink web interface.
- Assisted with management and automation of office board farm and other office resources and equipment.
- Assisted with configuration of an instance of the Linaro Automated Validation Architecture for a customer using Docker Compose and a Raspberry Pi.

## Quality Engineering Intern, Smith Micro Software Inc. May, 2016 to August, 2016

- Designed test sets and test cases for QuickLinks Mobile VPN Client using SpiraTeam.
- Developed and executed manual and automated validation for each new build of Quicklinks on various Windows operating systems.
- Used JIRA to file and track resolution of issues discovered during test cycle.

# Project Experience

#### **Computer Science Club Work**

Pantherview Mobile App: Collaborative Computer Science Club Project web application. Fetches data
via REST API's from the Western Pennsylvania Regional Data Center and a club-maintained Pitt API
hosted by Amazon Web Services. The app provides a user-filterable map view of the underlying data
including police incident records and information about Pitt services. Link: <a href="http://pittcsc.org/PantherView">http://pittcsc.org/PantherView</a>
(Language: Javascript)

#### **Operating Systems Project Work**

• **File System Primitives:** Implemented a file system via Linux FUSE (Filesystem in User SpacE) including block allocation, via linked-list allocation scheme, and operations including read/write, mknod, mkdir, readdir and getattr (stat). (Language: C)

## **Computer Architecture Project Work**

Cache Simulator: Designed and built a user-specified one-level cache simulator (direct-mapped, full-associative, n-level associative) including read/write and read-only variants and block-level replacement algorithms along with relevant statistics including hit and miss rates for various types including compulsory, conflict and capacity. (Language: C)

#### **Networking Project Work**

- **Web Server:** Built an HTTP client/server over TCP/IP sockets to allow a user to specify hostname, port and file name path and retrieve the selected payload, properly formatted.
- Multi-connection Web Server: Designed and implemented a multi-connection server using TCP/IP sockets to serve files to clients including the implementation of a simple select-based connection scheme. (Language: C++)

### **Current Projects**

• Cluster Computing with ClusterHAT: Current project in Advanced Systems Software using a Raspberry Pi 3 and a HAT (Hardware Attachment on Top) that allows it to interface with up to four Raspberry Pi Zeros. The purpose is to and design create a distributed computing infrastructure that fits in the palm of your hand, as well as a performance testing suite that measures performance with different configurations and workloads.

#### Code Day Pittsburgh, November 11-12, 2017

- Co-led planning and execution for the Pittsburgh instance of "Code Day", a nationwide 24 hour event, with 50 local participants from High Schools and Universities.
- Led day-of planning and responsible for expense management.
- Led workshop on basics of game elements and design.
- Provided basic mentoring to teams.
- Co-led "Code Cup", a nationwide problem solving competition between cities participating in Code Day.

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Skilled in various programming languages and Linux system administration.

- C (proficient, preferred)
- Java (proficient)
- Javascript (familiar)
- Golang (familiar)
- Amazon Web Services (familiar)

- HTML (proficient)
- C++ (proficient)
- Chef (familiar)
- Docker (familiar)
- C# (familiar)

## **Interests and Activities**

- Development & Operations (DevOps)
- Bass player in a swing pop band
- Audio engineering and music production
- Embedded systems development
- GNU / Linux Programming (Familiar with Debian, Arch Linux, Ubuntu, Raspbian) and system administration